<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Iron Battles]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ironbattles.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ironbattles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-12T23:45:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ironbattles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Freitas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Battles Alpha Testing Instructions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ironbattles.com/blog/2014/06/06/iron-battles-alpha-testing-instructions/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T11:19:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ironbattles.com/blog/2014/06/06/iron-battles-alpha-testing-instructions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is meant to instruct our testers on how to proceed during alpha testing phase.</p>

<h3>1. Registering to the alpha test</h3>

<p>If you would like to participate, just join our community on Google Plus. You will be able to download the application from the Play Store when your do so.</p>

<div class="g-community" data-href="https://plus.google.com/communities/103103676301107091838"></div>


<h3>2. Downloading the application</h3>

<p>Once you join our community, if you have not yet done so, head to the Google Play Alpha Test program and accept the terms to become a tester. You can access the program here: <a href="http://goo.gl/xbmCos" title="Google Play Alpha Test Program">Google Play Alpha Test Program</a>.</p>

<p>Once a member, you will be able to download the application from Google Play: <a href="http://goo.gl/m2fWTS" title="Download Iron Battles">Download Iron Battles</a>﻿. Note: you won&rsquo;t be able to find the application through a search since this is a private release.</p>

<h3>3. Providing feedback</h3>

<p>We value your feedback. This is the reason we are going through an alpha and beta release cycles. However, we need you to follow some recommendations when providing feedback.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>First and most important: this is an alpha release. Not all of the features have been implemented and the application is still in a rough state. Keep that in mind when providing feedback.</p></li>
<li><p>The focus of this test cycle is on the battle editor and import data utility.</p></li>
<li><p>To import data from Iron Grudge, first your need to back up your Iron Grudge data. Then just open your file manager of choice, navigate to the IronGrudge directory and click on a file to load. It should launch the Iron Battles application and a notification will be displayed on your Android device while the import is in progress. The application won&rsquo;t be able to access its own data during the import, but the whole process should be fairly quick. I tested the import with <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.metago.astro" title="Astro File Manager">Astro File Manager</a>﻿, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tomitools.filemanager" title="Tomi File Manager">Tomi File Manager</a>﻿ and the stock Samsung My Files application. The only requirement is that the file ends with a .sav extension.</p></li>
<li><p>Also important: please do not post app reviews or bugs in the play store during the alpha phase. We will use a tool for that. The play store is not meant to track bugs.</p></li>
<li><p>If you find a bug, have suggestions or just want to provide general feedback, please head to <a href="http://www.caravelahq.com/b/ironbattles02alpha" title="http://www.caravelahq.com/b/ironbattles02alpha">http://www.caravelahq.com/b/ironbattles02alpha</a>. This is the online utility we will use to track user feedback. You can log in with your Google account. The tracker is public and you will not need to request access. However, please fill in your name or PP forum name so we know who we are talking to :).</p></li>
<li><p>Do not enter tags on the bug editor. We will organize them.</p></li>
<li><p>Feel free to post on our Alpha Test Community. But avoid reporting bugs there.</p></li>
</ul>


<h4>Know Your Meta!</h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Battles Android App Permissions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ironbattles.com/blog/2014/06/06/iron-battles-android-app-permissions/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T10:56:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ironbattles.com/blog/2014/06/06/iron-battles-android-app-permissions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We believe transparency is key in developing a good relationship with our users. Nothing annoys us more than applications requesting tons of permissions without any clarification whatsoever of why they need them. You will find below the reasons for each permission we request. You might as well check our <a href="http://www.ironbattles.com/privacy-policy.html" title="Iron Batles Privacy Policy">Privacy Policy</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>android.permission.INTERNET: That one is kinda obvious isn&rsquo;t it? We do stuff online, so we need to access the Internet.</p></li>
<li><p>android.permission.ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE: This permission is required by Google Analytics. Our application itself does not check the network connectivity.</p></li>
<li><p>com.google.android.providers.gsf.permission.READ_GSERVICES: Required by Google Maps API. Allows the API to access Google web-based services.</p></li>
<li><p>android.permission.WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE: We write some stuff to disk. We will not, however, erase any files on your device.</p></li>
<li><p>android.permission.READ_EXTERNAL_STORAGE: Well, we also need to read some stuff from disk. We only read our own data and data that needs to be imported.</p></li>
<li><p>android.permission.ACCESS_FINE_LOCATION: Used when searching for Venue locations close to you.</p></li>
<li><p>android.permission.READ_LOGS and android.permission.GET_TASKS: This is required by our bug and crash reporting framework. We use this to track application crashes and act fast to resolve bugs.</p></li>
</ul>


<h4>Know Your Meta!</h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
